<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>react on Savitha Gollamudi</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/categories/react/</link><description>Recent content in react on Savitha Gollamudi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 17:52:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gsavitha.in/categories/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WTF is super() vs super(props)</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/2021/wtf-is-super-vs-superprops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 17:52:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/2021/wtf-is-super-vs-superprops/</guid><description>TL;DR 🚀 If you want to use this.props inside constructor of derived class, use super(props).
While checking react code, you might have come across a line super(props), sometimes super(). Ever wondered what&amp;rsquo;s the difference between two? Why do we need to pass props ? Do we always need to pass props ?
Consider the example below.
1import React, { Component } from &amp;#39;react&amp;#39;; 2class Game extends Component { 3 constructor(props) { 4 super(props); 5 this.</description></item><item><title>React Lifecycle Methods</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-07-react-lifecycle-methods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 18:20:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-07-react-lifecycle-methods/</guid><description>React Component Lifecycle Each component has several “lifecycle methods” that one can override to run code at particular times in the process.
These components comes with methods which allows developers to update application state and reflect the changes to the UI before/after key react “events”.
There are three main phases in a component&amp;rsquo;s lifecycle:
mounting updating unmounting Mounting These methods are called in the following order</description></item><item><title>React Forms</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-06-react-forms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 17:51:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-06-react-forms/</guid><description>Forms HTML form elements work differently than other DOM elements in React Form elements naturally keep some internal state. For example, this form in plain HTML accepts a single name: 1&amp;lt;form&amp;gt; 2 &amp;lt;label for=&amp;#34;fullname&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Full Name:&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; 3 &amp;lt;input name=&amp;#34;fullname&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; 4 &amp;lt;button&amp;gt;Add!&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt; 5&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt; Thinking About State 1&amp;lt;form&amp;gt; 2 &amp;lt;label for=&amp;#34;fullname&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Full Name:&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; 3 &amp;lt;input name=&amp;#34;fullname&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; 4 &amp;lt;button&amp;gt;Add!&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt; 5&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt; It’s convenient to have a JS function that handles the submission of the form and has access to the data the user entered.</description></item><item><title>React Events</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-05-react-events/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 14:55:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-05-react-events/</guid><description>React Events Review Commonly used React Events You can attach event handlers to HTML elements in React via special reserved attributes. (You can do this in vanilla JS too, though the syntax is a bit different.)
Event Attributes Any event you can listen for in JS, you can listen for in React.
Examples:
Mouse events: onClick, onMouseOver, etc Form events: onSubmit, etc Keyboard events: onKeyDown, onKeyUp, onKeyPress Full list Example: WiseSquare.</description></item><item><title>React State Patterns</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-04-react-state-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 15:52:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-04-react-state-patterns/</guid><description>Setting State Using State We know that setState() is asynchronous…
So: it’s risky to assume previous call has finished when you call it. Also, React will sometimes batch (squash together) calls to setState together into one for performance reasons. If a call to setState() depends on current state, the safest thing is to use the alternate “callback form”.
setState Callback Form this.setState(callback)
Instead of passing an object, pass it a callback with the current state as a parameter.</description></item><item><title>Intro to State</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-03-intro-to-state/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 14:57:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-03-intro-to-state/</guid><description>What is State? Thinking about state In any sufficiently advanced web application, the user interface has to be stateful.
logged-in users see a different screen than logged-out users clicking “edit profile” opens up a modal (pop-up) window sections of a website can expand or collapse, for instance clicking “read more” The state of the client interface (frontend) is not always directly tied to state on the server.
Why would the server need to know if a modal is open?</description></item><item><title>CRA and Modules</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-cra-modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 13:23:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-cra-modules/</guid><description>Create react App React is a front-end library — you don’t need server-side stuff. You can get react.js and react-dom.js from a CDN. You can transpile JSX in the browser at runtime. But there’s a better way!
Create-React-App is a utility script that:
Creates a skeleton react project Sets it up so that JS files are run through Babel automatically. Lets us use super-modern Javascript features/idioms Makes testing &amp;amp; deployment much easier.</description></item><item><title>Intro to React</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-intro-to-react/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:28:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-intro-to-react/</guid><description>Popular, powerful front-end framework.
Developed by and sponsored by Facebook.
Make it easy to make reusable view components These encapsulate logic and HTML into a class Often make it easier to build modular applications Components :
The building blocks of React Pieces of UI &amp;amp; view logic Classes that know how to render themselves into HTML A bit like this&amp;hellip;
1class Dog { 2 constructor(name, color) { 3 this.</description></item></channel></rss>