<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Savitha Gollamudi</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Savitha Gollamudi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:05:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gsavitha.in/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GCD</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-03-gcd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:05:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-03-gcd/</guid><description>LCM and HCF Factors and multiples: All numbers that divide a number completely, i.e., without leaving any remainder, are called factors of that number. For example, 24 is completely divisible by 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 12, 24. Each of these numbers is called a factor of 24 and 24 is called a multiple of each of these numbers. HCF or GCD : The largest number that divides two or more numbers is the highest common factor (HCF) for those numbers.</description></item><item><title>Prime Numbers</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-prime-num/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:04:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-prime-num/</guid><description>Numbers &amp;gt; 0 which are divisible by 1 and itself. Example: 2,3,5,7,11..
Facts about prime numbers: Every prime number can be represented in form of (6n+1) and (6n-1) except 2 and 3, when n &amp;gt; 0. 5 : (6 * 1 ) -1, 29: (6 * 5) - 1 2 and 3 are only two consecutive natural numbers, which are prime too. 1 is neither prime nor composite.</description></item><item><title>Basic Math</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-basic-math/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:04:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-basic-math/</guid><description>Progressions Arithmetic Progression : A sequence of numbers is said to be in an Arithmetic progression if the difference between any two consecutive terms is always the same. 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 is an AP series because they have a common difference (4-2=6-4=8-6=10-8)
Few facts about AP Initial Term (a): first number in the series Common difference (d): The value by which consecutive terms increase or decrease The behavior of the AP depends on the common difference d.</description></item><item><title>Recursion</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/recursion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 17:17:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/recursion/</guid><description>Intro to recursion What is recursion?
Recursion : A function calling itself directly or indirectly.
Directly:
1void fun1(){ 2 //somecode ... 3 fun1(); 4 //some other code... 5} Indirectly: Not a very common approach (Mostly direct recursive approach is used)
1void fun1(){ 2 //somecode ... 3 fun2(); 4 //some other code... 5} 6void fun2(){ 7 //somecode ... 8 fun1(); 9 //some other code... 10} 11 12 If you dont add a base case, recursion never stops and we might end up with stackoverflow(in case of java) or segmentation fault error(in case of cpp).</description></item></channel></rss>