<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on Savitha Gollamudi</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on Savitha Gollamudi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 18:32:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machine learning 101</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/intro-to-ml/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 18:32:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/intro-to-ml/</guid><description>What is Machine learning? How do we tell a computer what a cat is. Lets say we are asked to write a code to detect if a particular picture is cat or not. How do you do that?
The goal of ML is to make machines act more and more like humans because the smarter they get, they help us achieve our goals easily
AI vs ML vs DL vs DS Artificial Intelligence: A machine intelligence that acts like a human Detecting heart disease from images Machine Learning: ML is a subset of an AI.</description></item><item><title>Event Handling</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/events/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 15:18:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/events/</guid><description>Intro to DOM Events Events - Responding to user inputs and actions
Types of events:(some of the many)
clicks, drags, drops, hovers,scrolls, form submissions, key press, focus/blur mousewheel, double click, copying, pasting, audio start, screen resize, printing etc. Note: All events follow a similar pattern
Pattern:
The thing Event type Code to run button click change the color input hits return get the search results image mouseover display img caption for more info visit MDN Event reference</description></item><item><title>Manipulating the DOM</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/dom-manipulation-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:03:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/dom-manipulation-02/</guid><description>Properties and Methods of DOM Lets look at some of the important properties and methods which we use regularly
innerText &amp;amp; textContent innerText innerText gives the data in between the tags 1const h1 = document.querySelector(&amp;#34;h1&amp;#34;); 2h1.innerText; //My Web page 3const ul = document.querySelector(&amp;#34;ul&amp;#34;); 4ul.innerText; //&amp;#34;First2nd3rd&amp;#34; All the nested content is concatenated and output came as one object 5document.body.innerText; // we get all the text on the webpage, it doesnt matter it is nested or not 6//change the value 7h1.</description></item><item><title>Intro to DOM Manipulation</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/dom-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 12:27:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/dom-manipulation/</guid><description>Introduction DOM is a JS representation of a webpage. (JS window object on to the webpage). In brief, its a branch of objects (Browser turns out webpage into bunch of objects.)that you can interact with, via JS.
Note : Content inside the tags is the property of object Document Object DOM is a representation of a document object made with a bunch of objects &amp;amp; they are assembled into a tree.</description></item><item><title>Intro to Node - 2</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-node-intro-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 19:00:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-node-intro-2/</guid><description>Creating a Web server http module Gives us networking capability -&amp;gt; such as building a http server. 1const http = require(&amp;#34;http&amp;#34;); http requires a cb fn which gets fired off whenever a new request comes
CB gets access to 2 very imp variables (req and res)
Create a server
start the server -&amp;gt; by listening on incoming reqs
Create a server:</description></item><item><title>Intro to Node</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-node-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 16:09:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-node-intro/</guid><description>What is Node and why to use it? What is Node? Node.js is a JS runtime built on top of Google&amp;rsquo;s opensource V8 Js Engine. Node helps us to run JS outside the browser. It acts like a container to run JS code. V8 engine executes the JS code.
Why Node? With help of Node, we can use JS on server-side of web development. We can build fast, highly scalable applications.</description></item><item><title>GCD</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-03-gcd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:05:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-03-gcd/</guid><description>LCM and HCF Factors and multiples: All numbers that divide a number completely, i.e., without leaving any remainder, are called factors of that number. For example, 24 is completely divisible by 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 12, 24. Each of these numbers is called a factor of 24 and 24 is called a multiple of each of these numbers. HCF or GCD : The largest number that divides two or more numbers is the highest common factor (HCF) for those numbers.</description></item><item><title>Prime Numbers</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-prime-num/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:04:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-02-prime-num/</guid><description>Numbers &amp;gt; 0 which are divisible by 1 and itself. Example: 2,3,5,7,11..
Facts about prime numbers: Every prime number can be represented in form of (6n+1) and (6n-1) except 2 and 3, when n &amp;gt; 0. 5 : (6 * 1 ) -1, 29: (6 * 5) - 1 2 and 3 are only two consecutive natural numbers, which are prime too. 1 is neither prime nor composite.</description></item><item><title>Basic Math</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-basic-math/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:04:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/ch-01-basic-math/</guid><description>Progressions Arithmetic Progression : A sequence of numbers is said to be in an Arithmetic progression if the difference between any two consecutive terms is always the same. 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 is an AP series because they have a common difference (4-2=6-4=8-6=10-8)
Few facts about AP Initial Term (a): first number in the series Common difference (d): The value by which consecutive terms increase or decrease The behavior of the AP depends on the common difference d.</description></item><item><title>Recursion</title><link>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/recursion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 17:17:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.gsavitha.in/notes/recursion/</guid><description>Intro to recursion What is recursion?
Recursion : A function calling itself directly or indirectly.
Directly:
1void fun1(){ 2 //somecode ... 3 fun1(); 4 //some other code... 5} Indirectly: Not a very common approach (Mostly direct recursive approach is used)
fun1() -&amp;gt; fun2() -&amp;gt; fun1()
1void fun1(){ 2 //somecode ... 3 fun2(); 4 //some other code... 5} 6void fun2(){ 7 //somecode ... 8 fun1(); 9 //some other code... 10} 11 12 If you dont add a base case, recursion never stops and we might end up with stackoverflow(in case of java) or segmentation fault error(in case of cpp).</description></item></channel></rss>